<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abhinav Jha</title>
    <link>https://ajaxisme.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Abhinav Jha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 23:52:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ajaxisme.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Storing passwords securely</title>
      <link>https://ajaxisme.github.io/posts/understanding-password-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 23:52:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ajaxisme.github.io/posts/understanding-password-storage/</guid>
      <description>We regularly see a lot of cases of passwords being stolen from different organizations. Not even large companies like Facebook or Twitter are secure against password theft. While the security breaches have become common, companies have started focusing on security. One of the prime security concerns is the storage of sensitive data along with user information. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll go through different ways an organization can store passwords along with risks related to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empty a Kafka topic</title>
      <link>https://ajaxisme.github.io/posts/empty-kafka-topic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:11:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ajaxisme.github.io/posts/empty-kafka-topic/</guid>
      <description>Empty a topic in Kafka Kafka is a distributed streaming platform designed to be a highly scalable. It&amp;rsquo;s publish-and-subscribe model is very easy to follow and is endorsed by top companies and experts in the field.
There are some cases when you might need to delete all data in Kafka topic. There is no straightforward way mentioned in the documentation to achieve this. However, we can leverage the topic config to do that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ajaxisme.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:06:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ajaxisme.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>$whoami I am Software developer specializing in Data Engineering with a Masters degree in Cyber Security. Being passionate about programming, I encounter different opinions on the process of software development, including a lot of learning along the way. This blog serves mostly as an outlet of my views and a ledger for new things I encounter to look back upon</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>